Guide to the Memory Project Oral History collection, 2009-2016 | 民间记忆计划口述史 RL.10171
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Yunnan province | 云南省, 2010-2016
  - Wanbaochang Village | 玉溪市易门县铜厂乡铜厂村委会万宝厂村, 2011
    - Wang Guiying | 王桂英, 2011
      Wang Guiying (b.1937) is a resident of Wanbaochang Village, Tongchang Town, Yimen County, Yunnan Province. In this interview, Wang recalls life during the Great Famine. She moved to here from Baiyuguan after getting married at 19; she had five children when eating at People's Commune canteen. Although both her husband and she were not healthy, they still have to work in order to earn work points and get food. People then would eat what is fed to pigs now. The filmmaker's description of this interview has been translated into English.
      王桂英1937年出生，是云南省易门县铜厂乡铜厂村委会万宝厂村的村民。 在这段口述中，王老人回忆了大饥荒期间的生活。她19岁从白玉关嫁到这里，吃伙食团时带着5个孩子。丈夫和她的身体都不好，但不干活又拿不着工分、分不到粮食。现在喂猪的东西那时都会拿来吃的。
    - Li Hongying | 李红英, 2011
      Li Hongying (b.1937) is a resident of Wanbaochang Village, Tongchang Town, Yimen County, Yunnan Province. She said there was shortage of food at the People's Commue Canteen, she got one bowl of corn congee. She and others had to look for wild vegetables to eat. She also said that she had to work in the field with her baby on her back to earn work points so that her family would get a proper share of grains. Her son started working for the production team when he was 15.
      李红英1937年出生。她说吃食堂时，一顿饭只有一碗苞谷糊糊，要去找大量的也才充饥。她说自己要背着小孩子去干活，否则挣不到公分，粮食就分得少。她的儿子15岁就开始给生产队劳动。